Guide to the Lee Abbott Papers, circa 1965-2011 SPEC.RARE.CMS.0394
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1977-2011; Series 3
  - Tom, 1997 September 13 (Box 30, Folder 50)
  - Tom, 2005 October 5 (Box 28, Folder 104)
  - TWA Ambassador, 1979-1982 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified, 2008 February 3 (Box 29, Folder 103)
  - Ward, 2008 September 28 (Box 28, Folder 105)
  - Warren, 2011 November 11 (Box 28, Folder 106)
  - William, 2006 March 2 (Box 30, Folder 51)
  - Williams (Miller), 1986 April 22 (Box 28, Folder 107)
  - Yale University, 1993 July 9 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - "Z", 1997 September 12 (Box 30, Folder 52)
- Teaching, 1980-2011; Series 4
  Teaching includes letters of recommendation for students, clippings about Abbott's faculty activities at Case Western Reserve University and Ohio State University, fliers and programs for workshops Abbott taught at, evaluations of student theses, evaluations of colleagues, and notes related to Abbott's lectures. Materials are dated between 1980 and 2011. Folder titles based on the topics of the contents within the folder and folder titles with student last names are interfiled and arranged alphabetically.
  - Allison (Will) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Andersen (Isaac B.) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Bosco (Ronald A.) letter of recommendation, 2005 November 9 (Box 29, Folder 67)
  - Bracken (Katherine Teresa) letter of recommmendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Brock (Melanie Marie) letter of recommendation, 2011 November 8 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Case Western resignation for Ohio State University clipping, 1989 March 3 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Chavez (Linda) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Clausen (John H.) thesis evaluation, 2005 November 13 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Restricted; academic records
  - Cogley (Philip) project adviser recommendation, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Courtney (Russ) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Daher-Twersky (Jill) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Daniels (Jason) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - DeMartini (Alayna) letter of recommendation, 2011 January 19 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Dopkiss (Jessica) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Dunn (Samantha) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Elgin (Amanda Nicole) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Fabiano (Mark) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Fabiano (Mark) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Fabiano (Mark) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Falcon (Jennifer) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Fortkamp (Aaron) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Free (Pamela) instructor evaluation, 2009 March 18 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Restricted; employment records
  - Gilbert (Laurel) letter of recommendation, 2007 April 16 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Gilbert (Laurel L.) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Grant (Stephanie) letter of recommendation, 2003 November 19 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Guarino (Mark) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Hallal (William) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Handler (Shira) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Hatcher (Shantae D.) letter of recommendation, 2005 September 1 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Healy (Matthew Scott) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Hurt (Bryan) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Jones (Holly Goddard) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Jones (Holly Goddard) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Kim (Sylvie J.) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Lamp (Bill) letter of recommendation, 2009 April 2 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - LaRose (Christina) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Lewis (Jolie) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Logue (Anne Marie) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Lumpkin (David) letter of recommendation, 2009 March 7 (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Machart (Bruce) letter of recommendation, 1999 November 23 (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - Machart (Bruce) letter of recommendation, 2003 September 22 (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - Machart (Bruce Dalton) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - Magee (Kelly) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - Mattei (Louis Costantino) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - Mattei (Louis Costantino) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - McGreevy (Anne) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Minor (Kyle) letter of recommendation, 2005 February 22 (Box 29, Folder 42)
  - Minor (Kyle) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - Minor (Kyle) thesis evaluation, 2003 November 8 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Oestreich (Joe) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 44)
  - The Ohio State Lantern and Case Western campus newsletters, 1980, 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Ohio State University Graduate School's Summer Internship Program article, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Ortega (Devon Hunt) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Palacio (Derek) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 46)
  - Patton (Jennifer Gorman) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 47)
  - Peters (Stefanie) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 48)
  - The Plain Dealer article mentioning Lee Abbott going to Ohio State University, 1989 December 31 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Pollock (Donald Ray) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 49)
  - Pollock (Donald Ray) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 50)
  - P&W Writers Exchange competition, faculty judge clipping, 1990 December 6 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Ranalli (Amanda) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 51)
  - Reighart (Renee) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 53)
  - Renger (Todd M.) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 54)
  - Romines (Angela) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 55)
  - Russ (Dominic) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 56)
  - Salerno (Alexandra) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 57)
  - Stoddard (Samuel) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 58)
  - Teaching and grants correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Thorne (Amy) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 59)
  - Trimble (Elden) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 60)
  - Various letters of recommendation, 1993-1999 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Ventre (Gina) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 61)
  - Vickers (Curtis) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 62)
  - Wieland (Liza) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 63)
  - Wolfe (K.C.) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 64)
  - Wolff (Eric) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 65)
  - Writing rules and notes, undated (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Writing workshops fliers and programs, 1987-1989 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Ziegler (Jennie Burns) letter of recommendation, undated (Box 29, Folder 66)
- Talks and Lectures, 1981-2011; Series 5
  Talks and Lectures contains fliers, clippings, programs, and drafts of speeches for Abbott's speaking engagements, including readings of his work, book talks, lectures, introductions for other speakers, and appearances at writing conferences, festivals, and forums. Materials are dated between 1981 and 2011, and are arranged chronologically by date of the event, with undated materials listed alphabetically at the end of the series.
  - Readings fliers, clippings and programs, 1981-1997 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Speaking engagements clippings, programs and contracts, 1985-1990, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Plain Dealer Book and Author Luncheon clippings and programs, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - "Martians" reading at Wichita State University, photograph in campus newspaper, 1990 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Introductions by others for Abbott's talks, circa 1991 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - University of Tampa, Quilt coffeehouse guest speaker clipping, 1991 March 22 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Living After Midnight collection reading, "Daytona Daze" newsletter, 1999 June 11 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Herman (Michelle) recognition speech, 2002 May 29 (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - Roswell Public Library book talk, newspaper clipping and fliers, 2006 August 1 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - American University Visiting Writers Series interview responses, circa 2007 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Miller (Sue) introduction speech, 2008 January 13 (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - Spring Literary Festival flyer and program, 2008 May 7-9 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Ropewalk reading series program, 2009 February 24 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - McClanahan (Rebecca) introduction speech, 2011 April 7 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - Alber (Mike) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Barry (Rebecca) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Carlson (Ron) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - College of Arts and Sciences forum speech draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - The Gettsyburg Review Conference for Writers reading flyer, undated (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Gilbert (Laurel) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Harris (Buddy) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - Healy (Matt) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Introductions for other speakers, drafts, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Jones (Holly Goddard) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - LaVaque-Manty (Danielle) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - Machart (Bruce) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - Nichols (Ken) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - Ohio State University Newark talk flyer, undated (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Perrotta (Tom) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - Reading at Corbett Center, O. Henry Award winner, undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Spencer (Darrell) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 55)
  - Unknown keynote address draft, undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Ventre (Gina) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 56)
  - Wolff (Tobias) introduction speech, undated (Box 23, Folder 57)
- Personal, circa 1965-1968, 1984-2010; Series 6
  Personal contains newspapers, magazines, clippings, materials related to Abbott's Minister license, drafts of speeches for eulogies and a wedding, articles that briefly quote Abbott, scraps of unidentified notes, copies of other writers' works, a copy of a book proof where Abbott's name is listed in the acknowledgements, and Abbott's typewriter. Materials are dated from circa 1965-1968, and 1984-2010, and are arranged alphabetically by folder titles based on the topics of the contents within the folder.
  - Articles quoting Abbott, 1986-1989 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Book fliers and FedEx receipts, 1990-1991, 2005 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Book Forum, volume 16, issue 2, 2009 June-August (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Citino (David) remembrance draft, undated (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Columbus Dispatch, The Plain Dealer, and The New York Times newspapers, 1987-1990 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Grace (Ed) eulogy drafts, undated (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Magazines and newspaper clippings, 1984-1990 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Olivetti-Underwood Studio 44 typewriter in case, circa 1965 (Oversize item 1)
  - Rosen (Michael J.), The Company of Cats uncorrected proof with Abbott listed in the "Acknowledgments", 1992 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Roswell Daily Record newspapers, 1968, 1984 July 9-11 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Tucker (Jason) and Amy Monticello wedding speech, 2010 October 3 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified notes, undated (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Universal Life Church and State of Ohio Minister license credentials, 2004, 2010 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Writing by others, photocopies, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)